<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bursts on Peter Straka</title>
    <link>/tags/bursts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bursts on Peter Straka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/bursts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R package CTRE: thresholding bursty time series</title>
      <link>/post/ctre-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ctre-package/</guid>
      <description>The new R package CTRE is now available on CRAN. “CTRE” stands for “Continuous Time Random Exceedances”, which is a model for extreme values of bursty time series. The theory is desribed in another paper (html|pdf).
library(CTRE) flares_ctre &amp;lt;- ctre(flares) plot(flares_ctre, log = &amp;quot;y&amp;quot;, main = &amp;quot;Solar Flares&amp;quot;) The above time series are measurements of solar flare magnitudes by NASA1. Which observations are considered extreme is defined by a variable threshold \(u\) (dashed line, \(&amp;lt; 5\%\) of observations).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package MittagLeffleR: Using the Mittag-Leffler distributions in R</title>
      <link>/post/mittag-leffler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mittag-leffler/</guid>
      <description>Ricky Gill and I have created the R package MittagLeffleR, documented at strakaps.github.io/MittagLeffleR/. It is available on CRAN (and the latest development version on GitHub). MittagLeffleR calculates both Mittag-Leffler distributions; i.e. probability density, cumulative distribution function, quantile function and fast random variate generation. It was made possible by the Laplace inversion algorithm for the Mittag-Leffler function by Roberto Garrappa. Install it via
install.packages(&amp;quot;MittagLeffleR&amp;quot;) The Two Mittag-Leffler distributions Various journal articles (including my own) write about “the” Mittag-Leffler distribution, but actually there are two such families of distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extremes of Bursty Time Series</title>
      <link>/project/bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bursts/</guid>
      <description>Extreme value theory is concerned with the modelling and prediction of extremes in a series of observations. Accurate estimates of probabilities for the exceedence of extreme levels of temperature, financial loss, the number of defective nodes in a network etc. are crucial for the control of risk in a great number of societal systems. &amp;ldquo;Mainstream&amp;rdquo; extreme value theory assumes that events happen uniformly, e.g. yearly, daily, or every second, or that events occur at a certain rate (Poisson process).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>