<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistical-physics on Peter Straka</title>
    <link>/tags/statistical-physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistical-physics on Peter Straka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistical-physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fractional Diffusion where &#34;fractional&#34; varies in space</title>
      <link>/post/voffpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/voffpe/</guid>
      <description>The new paper (arxiv.org/abs/1712.06767)
 Variable Order Fractional Fokker-Planck Equations derived from Continuous Time Random Walks
 is currently under review.
The variable order fractional Fokker-Planck equation (VOFFPE), in simple form1, is \[\frac{\partial}{\partial t} p(x,t) = \frac{\partial^2}{\partial x^2} \underbrace{D_t^{1-\beta(x)}}_{\text{fractional derivative}} p(x,t).\]
 If you take out the fractional derivative operator, you get the Fokker-Planck equation (FPE). It describes the spreading of probability via a random walk:   Adding in the fractional derivative \[D_t^{1-\beta} p(x,t) = \int_0^t p(x,t-s) \frac{s^{-\beta}}{\Gamma(1-\beta)}\,ds\] results in the “fractional FPE”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Time Random Walks</title>
      <link>/project/anomalous-diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/anomalous-diffusion/</guid>
      <description>Diffusion is the net movement of molecules or atoms from a region of high concentration to a region of low concentration as a result of random motion of the molecules or atoms (Wikipedia).
Due to a discovery by Einstein (1905), a universal model for the random motion of microscopic particles is Brownian motion, whose mean-squared displacement increases linearly with time.
In many system with particles more complex than tiny molecules which interact with their environment (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extremes of Bursty Time Series</title>
      <link>/project/bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bursts/</guid>
      <description>Extreme value theory is concerned with the modelling and prediction of extremes in a series of observations. Accurate estimates of probabilities for the exceedence of extreme levels of temperature, financial loss, the number of defective nodes in a network etc. are crucial for the control of risk in a great number of societal systems. &amp;ldquo;Mainstream&amp;rdquo; extreme value theory assumes that events happen uniformly, e.g. yearly, daily, or every second, or that events occur at a certain rate (Poisson process).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>