<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-science on Peter&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://strakaps.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-science on Peter&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://strakaps.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Networks in Healthcare</title>
      <link>https://strakaps.github.io/post/2018-07-mja-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strakaps.github.io/post/2018-07-mja-paper/</guid>
      <description>See also the MJA podcast episode accompanying this article.
Our joint work (UNSW CBDRH and Statistics) which analyses Australian patient claim data using big network algorithms is now available on the MJA website. We have processed MBS claims data of 10% of Australians over the years 1994-2014, trying to shed light on the following research questions:
 What is the patient sharing behaviour of general practitioners (GPs): are there any meaningful clusters (called &amp;ldquo;Provider Practice Communities, PPC&amp;rdquo;) of GPs which collaborate and share patients?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUS-MIT Datathon</title>
      <link>https://strakaps.github.io/post/nus-mit-datathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strakaps.github.io/post/nus-mit-datathon/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had the privilege to participate in the NUS-NUH-MIT DATATHON and Workshop on applications of AI in healthcare with the UNSW Centre for Big Data Research in Health (CBDRH) team (Tim Churches, Mark Hanly, Oisin Fitzgerald and Oluwadamisola Sotade).
Thu &amp;amp; Fri: Workshop &amp;amp; Talks In the workshop &amp;ldquo;Deploying AI Solutions in Real Clinical Practices&amp;rdquo; by Dr Ngiam Kee Yuan (CTO, NUHS) we discussed
 The large NUHS (National University Health System) databases and their storage structure Data security and ownership Applications for access to data The always changing standards of diagnosis codes (ICD9, ICD10, SNOMED, &amp;hellip;) and the problem of matching doctors diagnoses to these codes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>